to calculate the temperature of the Sun
from Earth we must first find out what
light the sun emits the sun emits a
polychromatic light that is infrared
light visible light and even X-rays and
gamma rays you need to figure out the
wavelengths Lambda of each of these
radiations and with what intensity they
are
emitted if we plot all wavelengths with
their intensities in a diagram we get a
spectral intensity distribution of the
Sun from this distribution we have to
read off the wavelength Lambda Max which
has the highest intensity so we have to
read off the maximum of the
function then you can calculate the
temperature of the sun with the wans
displacement law to do this we divide
28978 * 10 power of -6 M Kelvin by
Lambda
Max in the case of the Sun the maximum
is within the blue light spectrum at the
wavelength 490 nanom or 490 * 10 to the
power of -9
M this results in a temperature of
5,900 Kelvin or
5,630 de C